<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Ethical Capitalism</title><link>https://ethicap.org/</link><description>Recent content on Ethical Capitalism</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 22:54:39 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ethicap.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Workflow</title><link>https://ethicap.org/workflow/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 07:21:11 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ethicap.org/workflow/</guid><description>The exact workflow will be adjusted over time to achieve our goals optimally, but I provide here the description of the first iteration.
Participating companies provide a list of up to 20 factual statements describing how their activities impact the Common Good.
Voters cast their votes online
Common Good Coefficients δ are calculated from these votes.
Goods and services are exchanged. Buyers pay the same regardless of δ. Sellers receive an adjusted amount.</description></item><item><title>FAQ</title><link>https://ethicap.org/faq/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 01:21:11 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ethicap.org/faq/</guid><description>That looks interesting, but it&amp;rsquo;s a long read. What&amp;rsquo;s the TLDR? What problems of our current system does Ethical Capitalism solve? What are the core beliefs underpinning this project? In one sentence, how is this system implemented? I see. You are ensuring payment for externality. Is it meant to replace the taxation system? It&amp;rsquo;s a good idea, but such an unprecedented change is scary. Why did you choose Plato as the emblem for this project?</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://ethicap.org/about/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 07:21:11 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ethicap.org/about/</guid><description>This website is built with amazing open source technology.
A big thank you to all the developers working on (in descending order in the stack) MathJax, PaperMod, Hugo, Go and FreeBSD.
Why is there no cookie consent pop-up on your website? I thought GDPR made it mandatory? 🧐 Because this website does not use privacy-invasive cookies. I am of the old-fashioned belief that websites should provide information to you, not the other way round.</description></item><item><title>Founder</title><link>https://ethicap.org/founder/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 23:21:11 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ethicap.org/founder/</guid><description>Sebastien Mouton has a master&amp;rsquo;s degree from Ecole Polytechnique (France) where he ranked first in financial mathematics and received the Outstanding Leadership Award. He has also obtained a master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Probability and Finance from Paris VI University to complement his education.
After gaining some experience at JPMorgan and Barclays Capital, he has built several businesses in algorithmic trading at Getco, KCG and Jump Trading, where his roles spanned from Quantitative Trader to Head of Trading Europe.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://ethicap.org/project/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 22:54:39 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ethicap.org/project/</guid><description>Ethical Capitalism Democracy 3.0 Our current blend of democracy and capitalism is the wrong governance model to face humanity’s modern challenges. Governments have repeatedly proven themselves unable to react efficiently to contemporary problems. I propose a new socioeconomic model that aligns tightly the efforts of individual agents to the Common Good.
The problem The current solution The Left&amp;rsquo;s approach The Right&amp;rsquo;s approach The proposed solution A new governance model Analysis Conclusion The problem Capitalism has been responsible for the most extraordinary increase in wealth and standard of living in the history of humanity.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://ethicap.org/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ethicap.org/contact/</guid><description> Comments, contributions, insults (it&amp;rsquo;s the internet after all), compliments?
Join the discussion.
Your subscription could not be saved. Please try again. Thank you for subscribing! Subscribe to the newsletter!
No spam, no BS. Unsubscribe anytime.
SUBSCRIBE</description></item><item><title>Get Involved</title><link>https://ethicap.org/get-involved/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ethicap.org/get-involved/</guid><description>This project is critically important but very ambitious. We need all the help we can get.
Here are some ways you can help:
Express your support by giving a Star to the GitHub project
Join the discussion on our GitHub Discussions. Any comment helps to build the community.
Report any typo you find on this website.
Translate some parts of this website to a language you are familiar with. Any amount of translation helps, you do not have to translate the entire website, or even an entire page.</description></item></channel></rss>